Harsha Vardhan G

 1 +91 9902488769
 | ■ hv2595@gmail.com
 □ github.com/harsha0609
 | □ linkedin.com/in/harsha-vardhan-946b6515a

Personal Profile

A Machine learning enthusiast and a vivid open source contributor with 2+ years of experience specializing in machine learning, application development, algorithms, and full-stack web development. Well-versed and seasoned developer in Django Rest Framework, ReactJs, and Natural Language Processing. Aspire to become a socially responsible software architect.

Education

National Institute Of Technology Karnataka

Surathkal, India

BTech in Information Technology

July 2016 - June 2020

• CGPA - 8.48/10

Narayana PU College

Bangalore, India

High School - Class XII PUC

July 2014 - May 2016

• Percentage - 98 (588/600)

· Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

Work Experience _____

Stratforge Chennai, India

Software Engineer

Sept 2020 - Present

- · Developed Multiple ML models for classification, deriving intelligence, and scoring.
- · Full stack Development, with designing and architecting the application. Multiple releases with agile development process
- Currently leading the product development as the technical lead with hands-on deployment routines, requirement gathering, effort allocation, and code review.
- Technical Skills: Python with Tensorflow, Django Rest Framework, ReactJS, Pandas, Redux, Docker, AWS
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills, Leadership

Startforge Chennai, India

Machine Learning Intern

May 2019 - July 2019

- Build a model with the team for generic resume sorting and intelligent clustering of CV's

OGS PayLab Chennai, India

Software Intern

May 2018 - July 2018

• Got exposure to day to day software development ethics with learning multiple technologies

Skills

Programming Python (Pandas, Tensorflow, Keras, NumPy, Scikit-learn. etc.), JavaScript, C/C++, HTML/CSS, SQL, Java

Web Development ReactJs, Django Rest Framework, Redux-ToolKit, NodeJS, NextJS **Miscellaneous** Docker, AWS, Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Microsoft Office, Firebase, Git.

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation, Leadership

Projects

RedFlare and Servedly

 Stratforge
 Jun 2020 - Apr 2021

- Developed an application that processes customer calls and does SSQA analysis, also processes live customer calls and gives various statistical
 insights and in-depth analysis.
- Technical Skills: Django, ReactJS, Redux, TensorFlow, Pandas, AWS
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

Intelligent Routing And Caching for Named Data Networks (Research Project)

NITK August 2019 - May 2020

- Worked on generic NDN routing and caching and studied the advantages of using caching policies for routing, implemented our own policies for both, and this implemented using reinforcement learning.
- Technical Skills: C++, Reinforcement Learning
- Soft Skills: Presentation skills, Teamwork, Logical Thinking, Thesis Writing, Literature Survey

OCTOBER 5, 2022

Machine Learning

NITK / Personal

- · Neural Style Transfer To detect if given two paintings belong to the same artist using CNNs.
- Twitter Suicidal Analysis to Predict the chance of Suicide based on the tweet.
- Predictive analysis for the prediction of the best group of physicians for Patient Diagnosis.

Medical Visual O/A

NITK Jan 2019 - May 2019

- · Developed model using LSTM to predict answer based on medical image and respective question. This was done as a part of imageCLEF 2019.
- Technical Skills: Python, Tensorflow with Keras, Pandas, OpenCV

Web Development

Personal

- Equalizer Live translation of video calls with multiple languages support.
- Multiple ReactJs Clone Applications such as Google Search, Instagram, Medium.
- Developed a custom Design System, worked on designing and implementing.

Misc

Personal

- Distributed Computing Parallel computation of skyline queries using map-reduce.
- Computer Vision Estimation of Optimal Speedbreaker Placement and Lane Expansion.
- Socket Programming A Banking management system(with GUI) implemented in Java communicates between systems through socket programming in real-time.

Preditive analysis for Debt Collection

Stratforge

- · To predict the probability of loan repayment and other predictive analytics for collection of debt and credit.
- This was implemented as a part of OceanPro Cohert-II.

Achievements_____

- Shortlisted as a finalist in a national level hackathon(MAKE-IT REAL) conducted by SIEMENS. (In the top 20 out of 600 teams).
- Participated and successfully completed ImageClef 2019 Medical VQA Task, an international competition.
- Ranked in Top 0.1% amongst 1,200,000 in JEE MAIN 2016.
- Pinnacle Performer of the Year 2022, Stratforge.
- Cleared the International Standard of Mental Arithematic Proficiency Examination.

Interests

Linux	Since 2016, as a developer, I have been in love with Linux. I recently switched to macOS, which feels like a premium to Linux.
Technical Writing	I love writing technical blogs, some of them are on my Medium and I seldom write for my company newsletter
Art	I have always enjoyed drawing since I was a child. Recently, I have shifted to digital art mostly on Deviantart.
Video Games	I always had the gaming gene. I mostly play on my phone and occasionally on my switch.
Swimming	I started swimming when I was 12. Going through submerged things while holding my breath was the most exciting part.

Music I enjoy almost all types of music may it be screamo, punk rock, bluegrass, pop, psychedelic, rap, and japanese.

Languages_

English	Professional proficiency (IELTS - Band 8.0 OverAll, (Minimum of 7.0 in Each Band)
Hindi	Native proficiency

Tamil Native proficiency **Kannada** Native proficiency

OCTOBER 5, 2022 2